The right spirit. The right attitude. The wrong color.
The Tuskegee Airmen is a war, history, drama film directed by Robert Markowitz.
During the Second World War, a special project is begun by the US Army Air Corps to
integrate African American pilots into the Fighter Pilot Program.
Known as the "Tuskegee Airman" for the name of the airbase at which they were trained, these men were forced to constantly endure
harassement, prejudice, and much behind the scenes politics until at last they were able to prove themselves in combat.
Hannibal Lee, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Walter Peoples, played by Allen Payne.
Leroy Cappy, played by Malcolm-Jamal Warner.
Lt. Glenn, played by Courtney B. Vance.
Benjamin O. Davis, played by Andre Braugher.
Major Joy, played by Christopher McDonald.
The Tuskegee Airmen is a 1995 HBO television movie based on the exploits of an actual groundbreaking unit, the
first African-American combat pilots in the United States Army Air Corps, who fought in World War II.
The film was directed by Robert Markowitz and stars Laurence
Fishburne, Cuba Gooding Jr., John Lithgow, Courtney B.
Vance, Andre Braugher, Malcolm-Jamal Warner, Allen Payne, and Mekhi Phifer.
The film explores themes of world war ii, fighter pilot,
training, based on true story, aviation.
The tone is emotional.